<Document>
# ANTAGONISM RULES
[italic]If you are not planning to attack or engage other non-antagonists in an antagonizing manner, then you need not worry much about these rules in particular.[/italic]
  
## Antagonists Versus Non-Antagonists
  - If you are not planning to attack or engage other non-antagonists in an antagonizing manner, then you need not worry much about these rules.
  - Non-antagonists are not permitted to attack specific non-antagonist (primary) stations:
  -- Expeditionary Outpost
  -- Lark Station
  -- Trade Mall
  --- If a player wanted to attack a non-antagonist station in the above, they will require explicit admin permission to do so.
  --- Other tertiary non-antagonist stations, and antagonist stations are permitted to be attacked.
  - Antagonists are permitted to destroy non-antagonist stations so long as it is in their objectives. Otherwise, they must follow the standard ruling
  - Non-antagonists may engage other non-antagonists in an antagonizing manner so long as they follow the rules of Self Antagonism.

## Space for Self-Antagonism
[italic]This server’s arrangement provides a space for players, should they choose, to all act in an antagonizing manner to other players. However there are still things they can’t do, or must follow in order to avoid griefing.[/italic]

  - Non-antagonists are permitted to steal from others so long as it does not strand/maroon them, or prevent them from traveling, or finding safety after the encounter.
  - Non-antagonists are permitted to kidnap others (with or without consent, the latter is how kidnapping normally works, obviously) so long as their prisoner is kept alive.
  -- In the event that the prisoner’s life is used as a bargaining tool, the kidnapper may dispose of their prisoner dead or alive wherever they please so long as they are equipped with a suit and helmet on, and with suit coordinates enabled such that they are capable of being recovered if the rescuers are competent enough to do so.
  -- If the prisoner kills themselves, then their kidnapper is free from the responsibility of keeping them alive, and may dispose of them however they see fit. (See Round Removal)
  
  - Non-antagonists are not permitted to raid station and outpost bank accounts for any reason.
  - Round removal (Ie. Gibbing, Ashing, etc.) is not permitted under any circumstances barring these exceptions:
  -- That the person being round-removed does not roleplay with respect to any of the rules defined elsewhere for this server.
  -- A prisoner kills themselves by their own hand(s) deliberately. Round removal is still not permitted as consequences of attempted escape, as all players have the right to fight for their freedom should they choose to do so.
  - Do not grief against AFK, SSD / Catatonic players.
  - All victims of non-antagonists must follow the 15 minute rule outlined in our Roleplay guidelines.
  - Self-antagonists ala non-antagonists are permitted to steal the contents of wallets, but are not permitted to force others to empty their bank accounts at an ATM.

</Document>
