<Document>
  #Null Sector Rules
  ## Introduction
  Failure to read or notice these fundamental principles of our server is not a valid excuse against criticisms, confrontation nor punishment.

  Many rules in the big four are naturally common-sense, but some interpretations of [MRP] may vary, thus they are required to be mentioned. All staff who have to deal with rulebreaks are encouraged to give second chances and act with clemency if there is room for it.

  [color=red]If any of the links do not work, use the guidebook version on the escape or (Numpad 0) menus. [/color]

  [color=red]These rules are expected to be read in their entirety.[/color]
  
  [color=cyan]Check the Null Sector Bible (NSB) through the Discord or WIKI for a rules read-through that doesn't hurt to look at.[/color]

  ## Roleplay Rules
  ### Rules Can’t Cover Everything
  Every example of a rule break cannot be defined as written, therefore, enforcement of the rules is subject to staff interpretation of the rule's intention.
  
  ### ERP Not Allowed
  - Erotic Roleplay (ERP), erotic content, or 18+ sexual content is not allowed under any circumstance.
  - Players must be at least 16 years of age to play on Null Sector servers. Any player under 16 years old will be banned until they are of age.

  ### Keep it in character
  Do not use information gained outside of in-character means, and do not say In Character (IC) things in the Local Out Of Character (LOOC) chat channel.

  ### Do not Grief
  
  ### No Metagaming
  - I.e. metagaming / meta-comms. This refers to communication between players outside of the game. Characters are otherwise allowed to know everything about in-game mechanics or antagonists, as well as keep persistent friendships and relationships with other characters when not for the purpose of unfair advantage by teaming up together for little IC reason.
  - Do not say LOOC things in IC either, like saying you “need to go afk because your dog wants to go outside,” in the IC chat.
  
  ### New Life Rule
  - After cloning, respawning, or taking a ghost role, you must follow the new life rule.
  - If cloned, resuscitated, or respawned, you don't have amnesia, but you can only recall vague details of who or what had killed you.
  - If taking a ghost role, you have no memories from any past lives for the duration of playing as a ghost role.
  - A 15 minute non-aggression period is required after respawning or being revived, so you can’t immediately try to go kill whoever killed you.
  - Don't act on anything you saw whilst a ghost.

  ### Follow General Chat Guidelines
  - Only speak in English, or in a permitted constructed language. (See Conlang Rules for details.)
  - Do not spam. Especially do not spam AHELP menu to admins.
  - Use AHELP menu only when absolutely needed.
  - Do not advertise.
  - Do not use Netspeak / 133T-speak (i.e. LOL, ROFL, XD, FR).
  - Words that are closely tied to, or intended to replace/imitate, real life slurs are not allowed.
  - Low roleplay (LRP) actions that have no regard for your character or the setting (Memes, silly copy paste spam IC) are not acceptable.

  ### Character Names
  - Your IC name must be realistic and fit into the game's setting. Some leniency is permitted wherein inoffensive names names of locations, brands, fictional people or names parodying off from them are fine. (e.g. Baul Sadman, Nuke Duken, William Weiß.) However:
  - Do not use numbers, symbols, titles or adjectives (I.e. Mr, Dr, Big, Old).
  - Avoid using character names of other well-known players, do not impersonate players this way.
  - All species have a naming convention, be sure to generally follow it.

  ### Separate Character and Player
  - Treat your character as a separate entity from you, the player. Your character's actions, feelings, and knowledge in-game should be based solely on the character's experiences and not your own as the player.
  - Previous experiences with other characters are allowed to lead to meta-friending, but you may not meta-grudge another player-character.

  ### Follow Antagonist Guidelines
  - All ghost roles have a set description for how the role should be played, you must follow the ghost role description unless informed otherwise by an admin.
  - Antagonists are not your friends. Whilst some may be neutral or accommodating, certain antagonists such as certain operatives, space dragons, or zombies are considered chaotic-evil and cannot be reasoned with.
  - Non-antagonists may not assist or work with antagonist Armadan crews, examples are such as watching mass scanners and tipping them off who to attack, pretending to be hostages, or knowingly funding for equipment/ships. Exceptions may be stated by admins, or otherwise explicitly by the nature of the antagonist group’s objectives.

  ### Follow Station Safezone Guidelines
  - The immediate 200 meters around all primary stations are considered safe-zones. Certain antagonist roles with explicit objectives may be exceptions to the guidelines below.
  - Absolutely no antagonist activity is permitted within this zone.
  - No griefing is permitted within this zone. This includes but is not limited to destruction, modification, removal, or otherwise restriction of use of any machine or device designed for public use, and the structure of the station itself.
  - Fights and confrontations such as shooting, attacking or any forms of harm are allowed, only on non-primary stations. (See Space for Self-Antagonism)
  - The theft of vessels is not permitted within close proximity to primary stations, but may be done only for the sake of travel, and not for the destruction of the ship. If you intend to steal a ship, the ship’s owner must not be left stranded on a non-outpost.
  - Joining a crew under false pretenses with the intention to mutiny and take the ship is not permitted.
  - Dangerous research like artifacts and anomalies must not be done while inside the safe zone boundaries of primary stations.
  - Do not transport any kind of creature or objects with the intent to cause harm/death, or bait into a conflict inside of primary stations.
  
  #### Primary Stations:
	- Expeditionary Outpost / Lodge
	- Lark Station
	- Trade Mall
	- All other stations are considered secondary (security), or tertiary (general locale) points of interest (POI)s.

  ### Security Forces and Station Staff roles are held to a higher standard of roleplay
  - Security Forces roleplaying as ‘bad cops’ forbidden. Strong knowledge of the ruleset is required before taking a security or command position.
  - Civilian and Security staff are expected to maintain a minimum of competency and performance on their jobs.
  - All players that are hired on as crew to the station as security or service staff, or through other direct jobs working for paychecks from the station, are considered non-antags and must not antagonize others into conflict on that station.

  ### Command roles are vital and are held to a much higher standard of roleplay
  - Command roles are expected and are required to maintain pay for their respective staff, as expected of the role. Payroll should be decided-upon by command roles, but at minimum must be $10k per round hour.
  - Embezzlement of station funds is strictly forbidden.
  - Both of these roles have higher access to station resources than should be allowed for most crew members. As such, if you ever end your shift early, always bring your ID with you, and always return to cryosleep so that your access cannot be stolen and the station funds embezzled. If for any reason you cannot (disconnect, crash, power outage, etc.) Please ping the game admins in Discord and we will handle your in-game character accordingly.
  - Docking fines are allowed by command staff, but not mandatory. Should a ship remain too long and stops others from docking or purchasing vessels, they are permitted to evict the ship away from the station by any means necessary, or sell it on behalf of the owners should they be SSD. All in all, time spent docked and waiting at the station is to be kept at a minimum.
  - You may not tax, lease, rent, or otherwise reserve the free and fair use of station resources and space to the detriment of the public or for personal gain. This includes, but is not limited to: charging fees for docking, charging for vending access, and moving station public resources behind access-locked doors to restrict access.
   
  ### Follow Escalation Guidelines
  - Antagonistic ghost roles, and pest ghost roles like mice are always fair game for attack. Don't grief non-antagonist ghost roles like familiars, drones, or pets without provocation.
  - Do not attack another player without a legitimate, explainable roleplay reason that could be applied in a similar, real-life scenario. A fistfight does not suddenly escalate into a gunfight.
  - Flag Escalation:
  - All players are expected to resolve situations and de-escalate IC confrontation, but are permitted to use lethal force if the the other party flags themselves.
  - A party flags themselves to escalate a fight by wielding a weapon, racking it, or by taking out any explosives / triggers.
  - After a Fight Ends:
  - If a fight results in someone being critically injured or killed, seek medical help for them. (See guidelines on Self Antagonism for resolution)
  - If at any point combat is disengaged and both parties leave the area, you cannot skip escalation and plunge back into a fight. What’s done is done.
  - Do not End of Round Grief (EORG), wanton attacking/killing/griefing other players is not permitted at round-end.
  
  ### Follow PVP and Antagonism Guidelines
  - Antagonists do not need to AHELP to request permission to start crews. They may act freely according to their role description or objectives. Many further addresses to permitted self-antagonism is covered in the “Space for Self Antagonism” guidelines below.
  - Spamming ahelp asking to be a an antagonist outright collaborating with antagonists without explicit permission will warrant a ban.
  - Antagonist crew roles may never exceed a total force of five members, including the Captain / Commander.
  - Non-hostile vessels that surrender and thus avoid escalations must not be killed, left stranded, completely bankrupt, or otherwise. All vessels being boarded must first attempt to negotiate before any hostile actions may take place as part of escalations.
  - Hostile antagonist forces that are known, declared, and confirmed, may be considered 'belligerent', boarded non-conventionally, and destroyed. All suspects taken alive must be adequately cared for and unharmed.
   
  ### Impulsive Purchases
  Don’t sell / resell ships impulsively during active combat as a way to avoid a particular outcome of a fight. Take the loss or win with honor and sportsmanship. Afterwards, vessel / profit recovery is fine.
  
  # Afterward
  Whilst the above applies to in-game as part of our Roleplay Standards, all of the below rules apply at all times, including between rounds, in-game and elsewhere in our community.
  They are fundamental, universal rules that must be followed by all persons regardless of context.

  ## Universal (Zero Tolerance) Rules
  You may be banned without warning should you break these rules.
  - [textlink="Click here to read the zero tolerance rules." link="FrontierRuleZeroTolerance"]
  
  ## (Self)Antagonism Rules
  In order to foster a community under a fierce yet fair openness without an official in-game police-force, rules about antagonism are required. Give these a read; they're very important especially if you're considering piracy.
  - [textlink="Click here to read the antagonism rules." link="NullRuleAntagonism"]
</Document>
