<Document>
  # NGC-SKR IAPETUS (UII Overhaul)
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BannerScience"/>
  </Box>
    [color=#a4885c]Hull Configuration:[/color] Small, Port and Starboard Docking

	[color=#a4885c]Crew Slots:[/color] 1 Pilot, 1 Research Director, 1 Engineer

	[color=#a4885c]Power System:[/color] 1x SUPERPACMAN Uranium Generator

    [color=#a4885c]Atmospherics:[/color] Gas Mixer, Premixed Air Connector

    [color=#a4885c]Weapons:[/color] 2x L85 Autocannons

	[color=#a4885c]IFF Designation:[/color] Civilian

  "After aquiring the Iapetus Blueprints, Ursadyne Interstellar Industries has overhauled it with an improved layout and updated safety features."

  # SHIP FEATURES

  ## 1. Bridge

  ## 1.1. Control Systems
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerStationRecords"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerShuttle"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerGunneryConsole"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NFHolopadShip"/>
  </Box>

  - Unlock the Shuttle computer using your ID card.
  - Use the Station Records computer to open up slots for the other crew members.
  - The Gunnery Console can be used to control the ship's turrets.
  - The Holopad can be used to directly contact other ships or stations.

  ## 1.2. Safety Systems
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LockerWallEVAColorPilotFilled"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShuttersNormal"/>
  </Box>

  - Check that the pilot's EVA locker is filled with a hardsuit, air tank, and mini-jetpack.
  - The button next to the windows can be used to toggle the shutters.

  ## 2. Science

  ## 2.1. Artifact Lab
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MachineArtifactAnalyzer"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerTabletopAnalysisConsole"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LockerResearchDirectorFilledHardsuit"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPressurePump"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BlastDoor"/>
  </Box>

  - Artifacts can be found on wrecks in space
  - Use a Multitool to connect the Artifact Analyzer and the Analysis Console.
  - Check that the Research Director's locker is filled with a hardsuit, air tank, and mini-jetpack.
  - The Blast Door can be used to open the lab to space. It is opened with the button next to the lab door.
  - The Gas Pressure Pumps can be used to pump air into or out of the lab.

  ## 2.2 Research and Development
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerTabletopResearchAndDevelopment"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ResearchAndDevelopmentServer"/>
  </Box>

  - The Research and Development console can be used to research new technologies.
  - The Research and Development Server can be used to store research data.
  - The Server is not limited to a single research focus, and can be linked to new machines.

  ## 2.3. Production
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Protolathe"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CircuitImprinter"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Autolathe"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ExosuitFabricator"/>
  </Box>

  - The Protolathe can be used to produce researched items and components.
  - The Circuit Imprinter can be used to produce circuit boards for various machines.
  - The Autolathe can be used to produce a wide variety of basi items
  - The Exosuit Fabricator can be used to produce robotics and their components.

  ## 3. Engineering

  ## 3.1. Power System
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SMESBasic"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SubstationWallBasic"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="APCBasic"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PortableGeneratorSuperPacmanShuttle"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LockerWallMaterialsFuelUraniumFilled"/>
  </Box>

  - Check that the S.U.P.E.R.P.A.C.M.A.N. generator unit is anchored to the floor.
  - Check that the SMES unit is anchored to the floor.
  - Check that the Fuel Locker has spare fuel.

  ## 3.2. Atmospherics
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OxygenCanister"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NitrogenCanister"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasMixer"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPort"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirAlarm"/>
  </Box>

  - Set the Ships Air Alarms to Filtering (Wide)
  - Ensure that a gas canisters are wrenched to the connector ports.
  - Check that the air mixer is set to ~21% oxygen, ~79% nitrogen (Confirm Crew Biology).
  - Enable the gas pump into the distribution system.
  - The white Gas Connector can be used to connect premixed air canisters to the ship's atmospherics system.

  ## 3.3 Other Systems
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Gyroscope"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GravityGeneratorMini"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LockerEngineerFilledHardsuit"/>
  </Box>

  - Check that the gyroscope is anchored, powered, and enabled.
  - Check that the mini gravity generator is anchored, powered, and enabled.
  - Check that the Engineering Locker has tools, a hardsuit, air tank, and a mini-jetpack.

</Document>
